# **Objective**

To leverage my experience in Automation and Software Engineering to work with an agile team and start up to build a world class product from the ground up. I want to work with an entrepreneurial team that takes ownership and pride of the products they build while always keeping the long-term vision at the forefront of all product decisions.

## **Education & Portfolio Information**

University of Oregon: BS Business, 2010 Github: www.github.com/johnfig

## **Professional Experience**

## GoodShop San Francisco, CA 2014-Present

#### **Software Engineer**

- Full stack developer working primarily with Ruby on Rails and Javascript
- Affiliate network integration with Popshops and AvantLink API
- Implement TDD with RSpec, Jasmine, Capybara, and Cucumber
- Migrated Legacy SQL Server Database to Postgres

# Byliner San Francisco, CA 2013-2014

#### **Software Engineer**

- Full stack developer working primarily with Objective-C and Ruby on Rails
- Open sourced boxBlur pod to help dynamically take a snapshot and blur views
- Built full stack iPad and iPhone iOS application while at engagement with Pivotal Labs
- Re-skinned entire application consisting of xib, storyboard and code based views
- Converted entire native app to 80% UIWebViews using JLRoutes URL parser
- Technologies Used: Objective-C, Ruby, Rails, XCTest, KIF, RSpec, Travis, Pivotal Tracker, Postgres, sqlite

# GoPago San Francisco, CA 2013-2013

## **Software Engineer**

- Full stack developer working primarily with Ruby, Rails, CoffeeScript, and Backbone.js
- Worked closely with Client team to build RESTful API's used by both iOS and Android
- Built admin tools for onboarding enterprise client accounts
- Cucumber test suite implementation to reduce regression black box testing
- Technologies Used: Ruby, Rails, RSpec, Cucumber, Backbone.js, CoffeeScript, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoid, Sidekiq

# GoPago San Francisco, CA 2012-2013

#### **Quality Assurance Automation Engineer**

- Test Driven Development with RSpec to cover code base with comprehensive tests of Models, Views, and Controllers on Ruby on Rails web applications
- Behavioral Driven Development with Cucumber to test front-end functionality
- Work on P2/P3 Bug fixes for development team

## **Additional Information**

# University of Oregon 2005-2010

#### **Entrepreneurship Club Member**

 Honed entrepreneurial skills by attending workshops concentrating on negotiation, corporate entities, intellectual property patenting, and effective marketing

#### Polytechnic State U.

## **Scholarship Athlete**

2005

• Demonstrated strong work ethic by competing at the Division-I National level

2133 Hayes St. | San Francisco | CA | 94117 | phone: (415) 852-8871 | john@johnfigueiredo.com